[
    {
        "question": "Which Chief Minister launched the Mukhyamantri Paushtik Alpahar Yojana to provide nutritious snacks to students?",
        "options": [
            "Yogi Adityanath",
            "Bhupendrabhai Patel",
            "Ashok Gehlot",
            "Shivraj Singh Chouhan",
            "Naveen Patnaik"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which date will Rajasthan observe Pravasi Rajasthani Diwas every year?",
        "options": [
            "15 August",
            "26 January",
            "10 December",
            "2 October",
            "5 June"
        ],
        "answer": "10 December"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which famous lake in Maharashtra is being proposed for inclusion in the UNESCO World Heritage Sites list?",
        "options": [
            "Powai Lake",
            "Lonar Lake",
            "Shivaji Sagar Lake",
            "Tadoba Lake",
            "Rankala Lake"
        ],
        "answer": "Lonar Lake"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the women-exclusive bike taxi service launched by Uber in Bengaluru?",
        "options": [
            "Uber Bike Women",
            "Moto Women",
            "Uber She Rides",
            "Women Rider Connect",
            "Ride Women"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state was awarded the Geographical Indication (GI) tag for its traditional handicraft, 'Gharchola,' known for its intricate designs and cultural motifs?",
        "options": [
            "Rajasthan",
            "Gujarat",
            "Punjab",
            "Maharashtra",
            "Haryana"
        ],
        "answer": "Gujarat"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Tikhir Tribe, which held its first-ever Log Drum Pulling Ceremony during the 25th Hornbill Festival 2024, is indigenous to which Indian state?",
        "options": [
            "Assam",
            "Nagaland",
            "Manipur",
            "Arunachal Pradesh",
            "Meghalaya"
        ],
        "answer": "Nagaland"
    },
    {
        "question": "The International Gita Mahotsav 2024 was inaugurated in which Indian state?",
        "options": [
            "Rajasthan",
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Haryana",
            "Gujarat",
            "Madhya Pradesh"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the Logistics Ease Across Different States (LEADS) Report 2024, which of the following states is categorized under Fast Movers in the Coastal States category?",
        "options": [
            "Gujarat",
            "Kerala",
            "Goa",
            "Tamil Nadu",
            "West Bengal"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state signed MoUs worth \u20b938,750 crore at the World Economic Forum in Davos?",
        "options": [
            "Gujarat",
            "Karnataka",
            "Maharashtra",
            "Tamil Nadu",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Indian state declared the Maha Kumbh Mela area as a new district in December 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Madhya Pradesh",
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Bihar",
            "Rajasthan",
            "Gujarat"
        ],
        "answer": "Uttar Pradesh"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which village in Gujarat has become India's first solar border village?",
        "options": [
            "Masali Village",
            "Vav Village",
            "Suigam Village",
            "Banaskantha Village",
            "Bela Village"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which state has the Ratapani Tiger Reserve, India's 57th tiger reserve, been notified, 17 years after its approval by the National Tiger Conservation Authority?",
        "options": [
            "Maharashtra",
            "Rajasthan",
            "Madhya Pradesh",
            "Chhattisgarh",
            "Kerala"
        ],
        "answer": "Madhya Pradesh"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state in India launched the 'Chocolate War' campaign to tackle opium cultivation?",
        "options": [
            "Bihar",
            "Madhya Pradesh",
            "Jharkhand",
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Rajasthan"
        ],
        "answer": "Jharkhand"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where has India\u2019s first White Tiger Breeding Centre been approved?",
        "options": [
            "Tamil Nadu",
            "Karnataka",
            "Rajasthan",
            "Madhya Pradesh",
            "Uttar Pradesh"
        ],
        "answer": "Madhya Pradesh"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the revised amount for the fixed deposit under the Dulari Kanya Scheme for institutional births of girl children in Arunachal Pradesh?",
        "options": [
            "Rs 10,000",
            "Rs 20,000",
            "Rs 25,000",
            "Rs 30,000",
            "Rs 50,000"
        ],
        "answer": "Rs 30,000"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where will the 72nd edition of the Miss World pageant be held?",
        "options": [
            "Mumbai",
            "Hyderabad, Telangana",
            "New Delhi",
            "Kolkata",
            "Bangalore"
        ],
        "answer": "Hyderabad, Telangana"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main objective of the Bhoo Kanoon (Land Law Amendment Bill) in Uttarakhand?",
        "options": [
            "To increase land ownership for non-residents",
            "To protect the state's cultural heritage and natural resources",
            "To promote industrial growth in hill districts",
            "To simplify land transaction processes for non-residents",
            "To encourage agricultural land purchases by non-residents"
        ],
        "answer": "To protect the state's cultural heritage and natural resources"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the international art exhibition \"Topographies of Tents, Terracotta, and Time\" being held?",
        "options": [
            "Mumbai",
            "Kolkata",
            "Hyderabad",
            "Pune",
            "Bengaluru"
        ],
        "answer": "Hyderabad"
    },
    {
        "question": "What significant feature does the Bhoo Kanoon (Land Law Amendment Bill) introduce for land transactions in Uttarakhand?",
        "options": [
            "It permits agricultural land purchases by non-residents in all districts.",
            "It creates a blanket ban on agricultural land purchases by non-residents in 11 hill districts.",
            "It allows free land transactions in the state for non-residents.",
            "It grants land ownership rights to foreign entities.",
            "It focuses solely on urban land management."
        ],
        "answer": "It creates a blanket ban on agricultural land purchases by non-residents in 11 hill districts."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organization launched the new advanced IT incubation centre in Salt Lake, Kolkata?",
        "options": [
            "Ministry of Information Technology (MeitY)",
            "Software Technology Parks of India (STPI)",
            "Tata Consultancy Services (TCS)",
            "Indian Institute of Technology (IIT)",
            "National Association of Software and Service Companies (NASSCOM)"
        ],
        "answer": "Software Technology Parks of India (STPI)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the proposed Aravali Safari Park located?",
        "options": [
            "Rajasthan",
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Madhya Pradesh",
            "Haryana",
            "Tamil Nadu"
        ],
        "answer": "Haryana"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state launched a witness protection scheme to ensure the safety of witnesses?",
        "options": [
            "Punjab",
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Haryana",
            "Rajasthan",
            "Maharashtra"
        ],
        "answer": "Haryana"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state has been allocated \u20b923,778 crore for railway projects in the Budget 2025-26?",
        "options": [
            "Bihar",
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Maharashtra",
            "Lucknow",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following states has contributed significantly to India's total utility-scale solar installations as per the recent achievement of 100 GW solar power capacity?",
        "options": [
            "Rajasthan, Gujarat, Tamil Nadu, Maharashtra, and Madhya Pradesh",
            "Andhra Pradesh, Telangana, Chhattisgarh, Odisha, and Assam",
            "Kerala, Karnataka, Punjab, Haryana, and West Bengal",
            "Bihar, Jharkhand, Uttar Pradesh, Uttarakhand, and Himachal Pradesh",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Rajasthan, Gujarat, Tamil Nadu, Maharashtra, and Madhya Pradesh"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Government of Tamil Nadu celebrates Thiruvalluvar Day in honor of the poet Thiruvalluvar?",
        "options": [
            "13 January",
            "14 January",
            "15 January",
            "16 January",
            "17 January"
        ],
        "answer": "15 January"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state ranked first in the Devolution Index Report 2024 released by Union Minister of State for Panchayati Raj, S.P. Singh Baghel?",
        "options": [
            "Karnataka",
            "Tamil Nadu",
            "Kerala",
            "Maharashtra",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state government signed an MoU with the Swiss-Indian Chamber of Commerce to foster international business collaboration during the Global Investors 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Maharashtra",
            "Karnataka",
            "Gujarat",
            "Tamil Nadu",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which Indian state was President's Rule imposed in February 2024 following the resignation of Chief Minister N Biren Singh?",
        "options": [
            "Nagaland",
            "Tripura",
            "Manipur",
            "Meghalaya",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state signed a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with the State Bank of India (SBI) and Union Bank of India (UBI) to offer insurance benefits to its government employees on January 1, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "West Bengal",
            "Assam",
            "Odisha",
            "Bihar",
            "Jharkhand"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state has topped the Fiscal Health Index (FHI) 2025 ranking launched by NITI Aayog?",
        "options": [
            "Chhattisgarh",
            "Odisha",
            "Goa",
            "Jharkhand",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    }
]